나 전에 원숭이 키웠잖아
Remember when I had a monkey?
그래
내가 무슨 생각을 했지?
What was I thinking?
얘들아, 뭐야?
팁이 20%라니
Hey, so, what's with the 20 percent
tip? Did I do something wrong?
내가 뭐 잘못했냐?
20%면 꽤 후한 거야
20 percent is a pretty generous tip.
그보다 더 후한 건 50%야
You know what's more generous?
50 percent!
- 더 후한 건 뭔지 알아?
- 네 속셈 알겠다
-You know what's even more generous?
-I see where you're going.
갑자기 웬 욕심이야?
What's up with the greed?
그래, 미안하다
I'm sorry.
I have to get new headshots made,
and they're really expensive.
새로 사진을 찍어야 하는데
너무 비싸거든
이제 세 장밖에 없어
I'm down to, like, three.
실은 두 장이야
Actually, two, because one of them
I blackened some teeth.
하나는 이를 까맣게 칠해서
왜 그런 짓을 했지?
Why'd I do that?
달리 돈 벌 방법은 없어?
여기 근무시간을 늘린다든지
Isn't there something you can do
to earn extra money?
Can't you pick up an extra shift here?
아니면 옛날 나처럼
돈을 구걸 하든가
Or, you know, I used to beg for money.
몸놀림이 이 정도만
나오면 도움이 되지
It helps if you've got
a little of this going on.
아직 녹 안 슬었다
Wow! I still have it.
그래
Don't you have an audition today?
Maybe you'll get that job.
잠깐, 너 오늘 오디션 있잖아
잘하면 뽑힐 거야
그러고 보니 의학실험용으로
내 몸을 제공하곤 했는데
Wait a minute.
I used to get medical experiments
done on me.
드디어 이해가 되는군
Finally, an explanation.
아냐, 그걸로 돈 꽤 벌었어
기억 안 나냐?
I used to get paid for
all kinds of medical stuff.
어디 보자
Let's see... Well, I don't want
to donate sperm again.
또 정자를 기증하긴 싫은데
집에서 뽑는 건 상관없지만
I really prefer doing that
at the home office.
그럼 피나 침 같은 건 어떨까?
Maybe they want some of my blood
or spit or something, huh?
- 조이
- 네
-Joey?
-Yeah.
What did I tell you
about talking while working?
내가 근무시간에 친구들과
잡담하는 거 삼가라고 했지?
그랬나요?
Do it?
10분전에 커피 시킨 저 손님이
자넬 두고 세 번이나 불평했어
That guy's been waiting 10 minutes.
He's complained about you three times.
어디까지 얘기했더라?
Now, where was l?
The One With Unagi
- 어서 와
- 그래
What are you up to?
무슨 일 있니?
We went to a self-defense class today.
호신술 수업 받고 왔어
아침 내내 남자들 가랑이를
걷어찼더니 힘이 다 빠진다
Kicking a guy in the crotch all
morning really takes it out of you.
Takes it out of you?
너희가 힘이 빠져?
Now we can kick anybody's ass.
이제 어떤 치한도
퇴치할 수 있어
After one class?
I don't think so.
겨우 수업 한 번 듣고?
아닌 거 같은데
You want to see me self-defend myself?
뭐? 내 실력 한 번 볼래?
가서 치한처럼 굴어봐
Pretend you're a predator.
Go on, I dare you!
빨리 가라니까!
Of course you can defend yourself from
an attack you know is coming.
물론 예상되는 공격이야
누구라도 막아낼 수 있지
That's not enough.
그걸로는 부족해
난 카라테를 장기간 연구했어
Look, I studied karate
for a long time.
And there's a concept you
should be familiar with.
너희가 반드시 알아둬야 할
개념이 있는데
일본말로 '우나기'라고 하지
It's what the Japanese call unagi.
혹시 초밥 종류 아냐?
Isn't that a kind of sushi?
No, it's a concept.
개념이라니까
맞아, 민물장어야
Yeah, it is.
It's freshwater eel.
Maybe it means that too.
물론 그런 뜻도 있지
연어 초밥 너무 먹고 싶다
I would kill for
a salmon-skin roll right now.
Fine, get attacked.
I don't even care.
너흰 당해도 싸
나 신경 끊을래
Come on, Ross, we're sorry.
Please tell us what it is.
그러지 마, 미안해
제발 가르침을 줘
Unagi is a state of total awareness.
우나기란 완벽한
경계상태를 말하는 거야
Only by achieving true unagi...
진정한 우나기를 획득해야
위험에 대비할 수 있다고
can you be prepared for any danger
that may befall you.
In case someone's trying
to steal your bamboo sleeping mat...
누군가 네 대나무 돗자리나
물고기 주전자를 훔쳐갈 위험?
or your kettle of fish?
It's one thing being prepared
for an attack against each other.
그니까 예상되는 공격에
대비하는 것과
Whole other story being prepared for
an attack. I don't know.. Surprise!
불시에 감행되는 공격에
대비하는 건 완전히 달라!
You knew that was coming...
물론 예상하고 있었겠지
그런 건 우나기가 아냐
but that doesn't mean
you have unagi.
If we made reservations, we could have
unagi in a half-hour.
지금 예약하면 30분 안에
우나기 먹을 수 있을 거야
잘났어
-Is Monica here?
-No.
- 여기 모니카 있냐?
- 아니
발렌타인데이에 뭘 줘야할지
너희들이 조언 좀 해봐라
I need help. I don't know
what to get for Valentine's Day.
Valentine's Day was two weeks ago,
so I wouldn't get her a calendar.
2주 전에 지나갔으니까
달력은 절대 주지 마라
그날 모니카가 근무를 해서
오늘밤으로 연기한 거야
She was working,
so we're celebrating tonight.
Why don't you book a day for
both of you at those romantic spas?
둘만의 낭만적인 온천을
예약하는 건 어때?
그거 정말 좋은 생각이다
That's actually a good idea.
물론 가랑이 없는
팬티도 준비하고
And, of course, crotchless panties.
모니카 애인한테도 자극적이지만
As appealing as that sounds
to her boyfriend...
오빠한테도 그럴 거야
and her brother...
We promised to make
each other gifts this year.
그건 안 돼, 올해는 직접
만든 걸 선물하기로 했어
- 그거 좋지
- 세상에
-I love that.
-You guys!
가랑이 없는 팬티도 못 만드냐?
You can't make crotchless panties?
You take scissors and cut..
- 그냥 가위로 거길...
- 됐어, 그만
Okay, okay, okay.
Making things sounds so much fun.
직접 만들면 재미있겠다
종이반죽이 눈에 들어가기 전엔
나도 그렇게 생각했지
I thought so too, until I papier-mached
one of my eyes shut.
I love papier-mache!
What did you make?
나도 종이반죽 좋아해
뭘 만들었는데?
I made a flar-lar-lar.
그냥 뭐 거시기한 거
- 그게 뭐야?
- 안 만들었다고
-What is that?
-Nothing!
So, what are you gonna do?
그럼 어떡할 거야?
너희들이 만든 거
하나 주면 안 될까?
Have you made anything
I can take credit for?
나한테 있어
양말 토끼를 만들고 있거든
I have, I have! I started making
little sock bunnies!
Oh, for crying out loud!
어머, 깜짝이야
잠깐, 그거 내 양말이잖아
Wait a minute. That is my sock!
Now it's your little bunny friend.
이젠 네 토끼 친구야
Okay...
좋아
진짜로 거시기하구만
This actually is a flar-lar-lar.
나 왔어
그래, 발렌타인데이 선물에
대해 뭐 좀 물어봐도 될까?
Can I ask about the
Valentine's Day gifts?
-Yeah.
-Do we have to make the entire thing?
그래
처음부터 끝까지
다 만들어야 돼?
Yes. Did you forget to make yours?
그럼, 선물 만드는 거
잊어버렸어?
Of course not.
물론 아니지
I just have to go to the place
where I made it and pick it up.
그럼 이제 내가
만든 걸 가져와야겠다
너무 기대된다, 최고의
발렌타인데이가 될 거야
I can't wait. It'll be
the best Valentine's Day ever!
I can't believe it!
Make the presents!
선물을 만들자고 하다니
내가 미쳤지
뭐?
-What?
-Just so excited to make the presents!
선물을 만들어서 너무 기쁘다고
이런!
안녕하세요
Hi, I'm Joey Tribbiani.
조이 트리비아니라고 하는데
제 체액을 기증하고 싶습니다
With all due respect,
I'd like to donate some fluids.
We're at the end of a research cycle
and not looking for applicants now.
진행 중인 연구가 막바지라
현재 지원자는 안 받거든요
That's too bad. I've been saving up.
아쉽군요, 모아둔 게 많은데
정말 제가 참여할 만한
연구가 없을까요?
You sure there's no studies
I can participate in?
- 이게 추후 일정이에요
- 감사합니다
-Here's a schedule.
-Thanks.
This one starts now.
이건 지금 시작하네요
Only identical twins are eligible.
It's a twin study.
그렇긴 한데 일란성 쌍둥이만
가능해요, 쌍둥이 연구거든요
But it's $2000!
2천 달러네요
Sorry.
죄송합니다
And this?
그럼 이건 어때요?
"Testing the Effects of Joey Tribbiani
on Attractive Nurse Receptionist."
'매력적인 간호 접수원에 대한
조이 트리비아니의 효과 연구'
Results are back on that one.
They're not good.
그 결과는 벌써 나왔는데
별로 안 좋더군요
-That was good.
-Yeah.
Danger! Danger!
에비야! 에비야!
로스!
What the hell was that?
이게 무슨 짓이야
A lesson in the importance of unagi.
우나기의 중요성에 대한
레슨이라고 할까?
You're a freak!
이 변태야
Perhaps.
그럴지도 모르지
Now I'm curious.
어느 세월에 비명을 그치고
내 엉덩이를 걷어 차실까?
At what point during those girlish
screams would you have kicked my ass?
All right, so we weren't prepared!
그래, 우린 대비를 못했어
I'm sorry I had to take such drastic
measures to make my point.
너무 극단적인 방법을
동원해서 미안하지만
난 너희 안전을 염려하는 거야
I just want you to be safe.
에비야!
Danger!
아하? 우나기...
Ah-ha!
Unagi!
콜 게디스
캐스팅 에이전시
2천 달러면 정말 큰돈인데
쌍둥이가 아닌 게 애석하다
2000 bucks is a lot of money.
I wish I had a twin.
Where could I find someone...
어디 가서 찾는다?
나랑 똑같이 생긴 사람을
who looks exactly like me?
야
Chandler.
챈들러...
I sensed it was you.
너라는 느낌이 왔어
What?
뭐?
Unagi.
우나기
I'm always aware.
난 늘 대비하고 있어
Are you aware that unagi is an eel?
우나기가 뱀장어라는 건 아냐?
-What's up?
-I can't figure out what to make Monica.
왜 왔어?
모니카 선물 때문에
네 농담을 하나 만들어주렴
Why don't you make her
one of your little jokes?
I'm going crazy.
Do you have anything homemade?
신경 긁지 마, 알았어?
혹시 네가 만들어둔 건 없냐?
You know what?
She'd love this.
이거라면 좋아할 거다
내가 6학년 때 만든
아폴로 8호 우주선이야
It's a replica of Apollo 8.
I made it in the sixth grade.
I could use that. I could say,
"Your love sends me to the moon."
뭐 이것도 괜찮겠다
'그대의 사랑으로 달에 이르리'
그래, 다만 아폴로 8호는
달에 착륙하지 않았어
Except Apollo 8 didn't
actually land on the moon.
그니까 이렇게 써
You can say, "Your love lets me orbit
the moon twice and return safely."
'그대의 사랑으로 달 궤도를
두 번 돌고 무사히 귀환하리'
I can't give this to her.
- 이건 안 되겠다
- 왜?
-Why not?
-It says "Captain Ross" on the side.
옆엔 '로스 선장'이라고
적혀있고
바닥엔 '난 모니카 싫어'라고
적혔네
And it says "I hate Monica"
on the bottom.
Danger!
에비야!
아... 연어 초밥
Salmon-skin roll.
그래, 어디 보자
Yes, honey, I made it myself.
응, 자기야
내가 직접 만들었어
I can't do it. I can't do it.
이건 도저히 못해
녹음한 테이프
A mixed tape! A mixed tape!
Hi! Ready to exchange gifts?
거기 있었구나
선물 교환할 준비됐어?
-Sure. You go first.
-Okay, come here.
그럼, 자기부터 해
- 자, 이리 와
- 알았어
Okay, it's not wrapped
because I just finished it.
아쉽지만 포장은 못했어
방금 작업이 끝났거든
But I made you a tape of what I think
are all romantic songs.
로맨틱한 노래를 다 모아
테이프를 하나 만들었어
What a great gift!
너무 근사한 선물이다
'오늘밤 그대 모습'도 있어?
Is "The Way You Look Tonight" on it?
We'll have to listen and see.
그야 들어보면 알겠지?
Oh, I love it!
Thank you so much.
너무 맘에 들어
정말 고마워
그래
- 좋아, 이젠 네 차례야
- 그래
You ready to open yours?
It's a sock bunny.
양말 토끼구나
Remember how I call you bunny?
내가 자길 토끼라고 했잖아
Not really.
언제?
I did one time.
And I want to start doing it more.
한 번 그렇게 불렀는데
앞으론 더 자주 부를게
-That's what this is about.
-I see.
- 바로 그런 의미야
- 그렇구나
Phoebe makes sock bunnies.
근데 피비도
양말 토끼를 만들던데
No, she doesn't.
What she makes, they're sock rabbits.
아냐, 피비가 만드는 건
집토끼 종류거든
이거랑 완전히 달라
그래, 알았어
They're completely different.
Okay, okay.
I didn't make it!
못 만들었어, 오늘밤 일을
까맣게 잊고 있었지 뭐야
I forgot about tonight and that we're
supposed to make the presents.
괜찮아, 난...
It's okay.
아니, 괜찮지 않아
No, it's not okay.
You're so incredible.
넌 오랜 시간과 노력을 들여
이 테이프를 만들어줬잖아
You went through all this time
and effort to make this tape.
내가 꼭 보상할게, 정말이야
I'll make this up to you.
I will.
I am going to cook you
anything you want in here.
여기서 자기가 원하는 건
뭐든 요리해줄게
And I'm going to do anything
you want in there.
또 저기서 자기가 시키는 건
뭐든 할 용의가 있어
Well, I did put a lot of thought
into the tape.
사실 그 테이프
진짜 힘들게 만들었어
You are way too young
to have seen that.
넌 이런 거 보기엔 너무 어려
Your birthday's in a month and a half.
자기 생일 한 달 정도 남았는데
What if I forget to get you
a present for that too?
그때도 선물 잊으면
어떡할 거야?
완벽하게 100% 용서해줄게
You are totally and completely
100 percent forgiven.
We've got to wash that.
- 그거 빨아야겠다
- 맞아
Remember that jacket you loved
that was too expensive?
맘에는 드는데 비싸다고
안 샀던 그 재킷 기억나?
You have done enough.
넌 할 만큼 했어
I'll wake up early and get it.
아침 일찍 가서 사야겠다
No, you don't..
Get it in black, not brown.
됐다니까... 갈색보단
검은색이 낫더라
케이크 다 됐다
Your cake is ready.
옛말 그른 거 하나 없네
'섹스하고 케이크 먹고'
It's like that old saying,
"Have sex, eat some cake."
Hey, Mon. Hey, Chan.
Just getting a soda.
안녕, 모니카
그래, 챈들러
소다수 있지?
Who the hell are you?
아저씨 누구세요?
조이야
I'm Joey.
How are you doing?
'안녕하셔'
No! No! No! No! No!
그게 아니잖아
How you doing?
'안녕하쇼'
Damn it, Carl! Go wait in the hall.
안녕하쇼, 젠장!
복도에서 기다려
칼 대신 내가 사과할게
I've got to apologize
on behalf of Carl.
Who the hell is Carl?
칼이 대체 누군데?
Did I not mention?
내가 얘기 안 했나?
Carl is a guy I hired to be my twin
for a medical research project.
의학 연구 프로젝트 때문에
내 일란성 쌍둥이로 고용했다
Sometimes the good ideas are
right in front of you.
어떻게 그런 기발한
생각을 다 하셨을까?
It sounds crazy, but it might work.
The only problem is Carl's acting...
약간 엉뚱하지만 잘될 거야
유일한 문제는 칼의 연기지
The only problem?
유일한 문제?
He's the reason I didn't get that big
commercial a couple of years ago.
그래, 저 녀석 때문에 예전에
'미닛 메이드' 광고를 놓쳤어
We were supposed to be brothers,
but he messed up.
형제 역인데 쟤가 망쳤잖아
이봐요, 저 케이크
한 조각 먹어도 되죠?
Can I get a piece of that cake?
Pizza! We like pizza!
Get out!
피자야, 우린 피자를 좋아해
나가!
-Pat Sajak?
-Yep.
팻 세이작?
그럼
-Alex Trebek?
-Of course.
알렉스 트레벡?
물론이야
-Chuck Woolery?
-Definitely.
척 울러리
당연하지
내가 엉덩이를 걷어차지 못할
게임 쇼 호스트는 한 명도 없어
You will not find a single game-show
host whose ass I cannot kick.
-Say it!
-Say we are unagi!
말해
우리가 우나기라고 말해
It's not something you are,
it's something you have.
그건 사람이 아니라
정신상태야
Say it!
말하라니까
I could easily get out of this...
내가 일어나면 너희들
크게 다치는 수가 있어
but there's a chance
you could get very, very hurt!
Carl, we're next. Now remember,
what is this not gonna be?
좋아, 우리가 다음이야
명심해
뭘 조심하라고?
-Another Minute Maid fiasco.
-That's right.
- 몇 년 전 '미닛 메이드' 사건
- 바로 그거야
And what are you not gonna do?
그럼 어떡해야 되지?
-I'm not gonna talk because..
-Damn it, Carl!
- 입을 꾹 다물고...
- 젠장, 칼
다음은 누구죠?
Can I have the next one, please?
Thank you.
고마워요
Joey and Tony Tribbiani.
조이와 토니 트리비아니
That's us.
저흽니다
But this is a study
for identical twins.
하지만 이건
일란성 쌍둥이 연구입니다
That's right. $2000.
그렇죠, 2천 달러
But you're not identical twins.
두 분은 일란성 쌍둥이가
아니잖아요
젠장, 칼!
Damn it, Carl!
Oh, my good God.
하느님 맙소사
자기야
Continuing the countdown of your
favorite meals.
역시 자기가 좋아하는 음식이야
Tonight, number three:
오늘밤은 그 세 번째 순서
Macaroni and cheese
with cut-up hot dogs.
마카로니 치즈와 다진 핫도그
Look, you have done enough.
You have to stop this now.
그 정도면 충분해
이럴 필요 없다니까
오늘밤까지만 할 거야
I will, but not tonight.
배경음악으로는
For dinner music, I thought we could
listen to that tape that you made me.
자기가 만들어준
테이프를 듣는 거야
Oh, the mixed tape.
내가 녹음한 거?
'오늘밤 그대 모습'이 있잖아
"The Way You Look Tonight" is on here.
Dance with me.
춤출래?
You are just the sweetest.
이렇게 사랑스러운
사람이 또 있을까
I love the way you look every night,
Chandler.
난 매일 밤 그대 모습을
사랑해요, 챈들러
That's why I made you this tape.
그래서 이 테이프를 만든 거야
생일 축하해, 당신의 재니스가
Happy birthday!
Love, Janice!
아니, 자기가 더 사랑스러워
No, you're the sweetest.
Okay, ladies, that ends today's class.
좋아요, 여러분
오늘 수업을 마칩니다
늘 조심하는 거 잊지 마세요
Remember, be safe out there.
훌륭한 수업이네요
-Great class.
-Thanks.
- 감사합니다
- 네, 유심히 봤거든요
I was watching.
A couple of questions:
몇 가지 궁금한 게 있는데
You know that last move...
마지막에 여자가 발을 걸어서
바닥에 쓰러뜨린 다음
where that woman tripped you
and pinned you to the floor?
어떻게 하는 거죠?
What would you do next?
열쇠를 꺼내서 남자의...
She'd take the keys
and jam them in your..
그게 아니라
당신이 어떻게 하냐고요
No, no. What would you do next?
-Who, me, the attacker?
-Yes, that's right.
- 공격한 사람이?
- 네, 그렇죠
Why?
왜요?
I tried attacking two women.
Did not work.
내가 두 여자를 공격하다
실패했거든요
What?
뭐요?
No, it's okay.
They're my friends.
아뇨, 괜찮아요
친구들이니까
In fact, I was married to one of them.
실은 그 중 한 여자랑
결혼까지 했었죠
그러니까 전처를
공격했다 이 겁니까?
You attacked your ex-wife?
아뇨, 아니죠
시도만 했다고요
Oh, no. No, no.
I tried.
But I couldn't.
That's why I'm here.
잘 안 돼서 여기 온 거죠
우리 둘이서 걔들을
공격하면 어떨까요?
Maybe we could attack them together!
That's a no.
안 되겠죠?
정말 진심으로 진짜 미안해
I am so, so, so, so sorry.
여기서 자기가 원하는 건
뭐든 요리해주고
And I will cook
anything you want in here...
저 안에서 자기가
시키는 건 뭐든 할게
and do anything you want in there.
이쪽은 상관없지만
저쪽은 지금 장난해?
Yeah, you will!
And are you kidding me?
이러지 마, 우리의
발렌타인데이잖아
Come on, Monica,
it's our Valentine's Day.
이렇게 부탁할게
Please, please, please, please?
Okay.
- 좋아
- 그래야지
내 즐거운 발렌타인
달콤하고 유쾌한 발렌타인
우리 이제 들어가는 거야?
-So are we going in there?
-I am!
나만
아하
Nowhere to run.
달아날 구멍은 없지?
I don't like sitting up here.
I'm gonna go over..
나 여기 못 앉겠어
- 당장 가서...
- 저 사람들이 먼저 왔잖아
No, they got here first.
뭐야?
-Why is Ross doing that?
-Danger!
로스 쟤 왜 저래?
- 에비야!
- 글쎄...
Oh, my God!
Why is he jumping on those women?
맙소사
왜 저 여자들한테 덤벼들지?
We should help them.
도와줘야겠다
I don't think they need any help.
도와줄 필요는 없겠는데?